还记得我以前养过猴子吗
Remember when l had a monkey?
我当时脑子在抽什么风啊
Yeah, what..what was l thinking?
为什么才给20%的小费啊
Hey, so, what's with the 20 percent tip?
我做错什么了吗
Did l do something wrong?
给你20%很大方了
20 percent is a pretty generous tip, Joe.
你知道多少更大方吗  50%
You know what's more generous than that? 50 percent!
你知道怎样更大方吗
You know what's even more generous than that?
我知道你想说什么了
l see where you're going.
干嘛突然这么贪钱啊  乔伊
What's up with the greed, Joe?
好吧  对不起  只是...
All right, l'm sorry, you guys. But just...
我得照新的大头照
l have to get new headshots made,
但是价格都好贵
and they're really expensive, you know.
我挑了三张
l'm down to, like, three.
其实只剩两张了
Actually, two, because one of them...
有一张的牙齿  被我涂黑了  我真白痴啊
l kind of blackened some teeth. Why'd l do that?
没其他方法赚外快了吗
lsn't there something you can do to earn a little extra money?
例如说  在这里多轮一班
I mean, can't you pick up, I don't know, an extra shift here?
或是我以前当过乞丐
Or, you know, l used to beg for money.
当然  如果你能这样
Of course it helps if you've got, you know,
那就更是手到钱来啦
a little of this going on.
我现在还会
Wow! l still have it.
等等  你今天不是有试镜吗
Wait, wait. Don't you have an audition today?
-也许你会入选啊  -真幽默
- Maybe you'll get that job. - Oh, hahaha.
等等
Oh, wait a minute.
我以前常参加医学实验
l used to get medical experiments done on me all the time.
难怪变成这样
Ah, finally, an explanation.
不是  我以前常靠这个赚钱  记得吗
No, l used to get paid for all kinds of medical stuff, remember?
我想想
Let's see.... well,
我不想再捐精了
l don't want to donate sperm again.
这种事我只喜欢在家做
l really prefer doing that at the home office, you know.
也许医院会要我的血或口水什么
Maybe they want some of my blood or spit or something, huh?
-乔伊  -怎样
- Joey? - Yeah.
我是怎么说工作时跟朋友聊天的
What did l tell you about talking to your friends while working?
放胆聊
Do it?
那个人等咖啡等了十分钟
That guy's been waiting for his coffee for 10 minutes.
投诉你三次了
He's complained about you three times.
我讲到哪里
Now, where was l?
你们干嘛去了
Hey, what have you guys been up to?
我们今天去学防身术
We went to a self-defense class today.
对  踢了一早上的胯下
Yeah. Kicking a guy in the crotch all morning
什么鸟气都没了
really takes it out of you.
你们开心  人家就...
Takes it out of you.
-现在我们谁都能修理  -没错
- Now we can kick anybody's ass. - Yes.
才一堂课  不可能
After one class? l don't think so.
干嘛  你想看我自卫吗
What? You want to see me self-defend myself?
去那边假装你是性侵者
Go over there and pretend you're a sexual predator.
有种就去啊
Go on, l dare you!
你当然可以抵挡已知的攻击
Of course you can defend yourself from an attack you know is coming.
但那样还不够
That's not enough.
听着  我学了很久的控手道
Look, l studied karate for a long time.
有个概念你们一定要了解
And there's a concept you should really be familiar with.
日文叫做"漫臾"
lt's what the Japanese call unagi.
那不是一种寿司吗
lsn't that a kind of sushi?
-那是一种概念  -是寿司没错
- No, it's a concept. - Yeah, it is. It is.
就是鳗鱼嘛
lt's freshwater eel.
或许是同一个字...
Maybe it means that too.
我现在好想吃鲑鱼手握寿司啊
l would kill for a salmon-skin roll right now.
好  被攻击活该  我不在乎
You know, fine, get attacked. l don't even care.
罗斯  对不起
Come on, Ross, we're sorry.
快告诉我们是什么意思
Please tell us what it is.
漫臾是一种全知的境界
Unagi is a state of total awareness, okay?
只有达到真正的漫臾
Only by achieving true unagi...
才能应付任何可能的危险
...can you be prepared for any danger that may befall you.
你是说有人要偷你的竹席
You mean in case someone's trying to steal your bamboo sleeping mat...
或鱼壶的时候吗
...or your kettle of fish?
我的重点是
All I am saying it's one thing
应付已知要来临的攻击是一回事
being prepared for an attack against, like each other.
应付突如其来的袭击又是另一回事
Whole other story being prepared for an attack.
比如说...  意外
l don't know -- surprise!
好吧  这次你们料到了
All right you knew that was coming...
但不表示你们有漫臾
...but that doesn't mean you have unagi.
你知道吗   如果现在订位
Oh, you know what? lf we made reservations,
半小时后就能吃到鳗鱼
we could have unagi in a half-hour.
-莫妮卡在吗  -不在
- ls Monica here? - No.
帮个忙
Okay, look, l need your help.
我不知道该送什么情人节礼物
l don't know what to get for Valentine's Day.
情人节已经过两星期了
Well, valentine's Day was two weeks ago,
所以我肯定不会送她日历
so l wouldn't get her a calendar.
她情人节那天要上班
She was working on Valentine's Day.
所以我们改到今晚过
so we're celebrating it tonight.
你们何不订一个浪漫的双人SPA
Why don't you book a day for both of you at those romantic spas?
乔伊  这个主意很棒
Joey, that's actually a good idea.
当然  要穿胯下开洞的内裤哦
And, of course, crotchless panties.
虽然对她的男友来说很有吸引力嘛...
Well, as appealing as that sounds to her boyfriend...
也许对她的哥哥也是
...and her brother....
但不行  我们说好今年要自己做礼物
I can't do that. We promised to make each other gifts this year.
-我喜欢  -真好
- Oh, l love that. - You guys!
你不会做开洞的内裤吗
You can't make crotchless panties?
只需拿一把剪刀  然后剪...
You take, you take a pair of scissors and you just cut…
够了  够了
Okay, okay, okay.
做礼物  听起来好好玩
So making things sounds so much fun.
我也这么认为  直到我的眼睛糊到纸黏土
l thought so too, until l papier-mached one of my eyes shut.
我喜欢纸黏土  你做了什么
l love papier-mache! What did you make?
我做了  啦啦啦
l made a flar-lar-lar.
-那是什么  -什么也不是
- What is that? - Nothing!
你要怎么办
So, what are you gonna do?
你们有没有做什么  能让我用的东西
Have you guys made anything? Maybe l can take credit for?
我有  我有
l have, l have!
我做了袜子兔
l started making little sock bunnies!
了不起吧
Oh, for crying out loud!
等等  那是我的袜子
Wait a minute. That is my sock!
现在它是你的兔兔朋友
Now it's your little bunny friend.
好
Okay....
这是一个  啦啦啦
This...this actually is a flar-lar-lar.
亲爱的
Hey, honey.
-我能不能问你情人节礼物的事  -可以啊
- Can l ask a question about the Valentine's Day gifts? - Yeah.
-全都要自己做吗  -当然
- Do we have to make the entire thing? - Yes.
怎么了  你忘了做了吗
Why? Did you forget to make yours?
当然没有
Of course, of course not.
我只是得去做的地方拿回来
l just have to go over the place where l made it and pick it up.
好
Okay.
我好期待哦  这会是最棒的情人节
l can't wait. lt'll be the best Valentine's Day ever!
我居然忘了  要做礼物这件事
l can't believe it! Make the presents! Make the presents!
-什么  -要做礼物好兴奋喔
- What? - Just so excited to make the presents!
你好  我是乔伊·崔比安尼
Hi, l'm Joey Tribbiani.
我诚心诚意地想捐赠一些液体
With all due respect, l'd like to donate some fluids.
现在这个研究项目已经快要结束
We're actually at the end of one of our research cycle
我们不再需要志愿者了
so we are not looking for applicants right now.
真可惜  我存了一阵子呢
That's too bad. l've kinda been saving up.
真的没有我能参加的项目了吗
You sure there's no studies l can participate in?
-这是我们接下来的研究项目表  -谢谢
- Well, Here's a schedule of what's coming up. - Thanks.
这个已经开始了呢
But this one starts now.
没错  但只限同卵双胞胎
Oh, that one is available now, but only identical twins are eligible.
-那是双胞胎研究  -但是有两千块钱呢
- lt's a twin study. - But it's $2000!
抱歉
Sorry.
那这个呢
How about this one?
"测试乔伊·崔比安尼
"Testing the Effects of Joey Tribbiani
对美女接待的影响力实验"
on Attractive Nurse Receptionist."
结果已经出来了  不太理想
We already got results are back on that one. They're not good.
-那太好了  -对
- That was good. - Yeah.
危险  危险
Danger! Danger!
你搞屁啊
What the hell was that?
让你们认识漫臾的重要
A lesson in the importance of unagi.
你个变态
You're a freak!
或许吧
Perhaps.
我很好奇
Now l'm curious.
你们要哇哇叫到什么时候
At what point during those girlish screams
才开始修理我呢
would you have begun to kick my ass?
好吧  我们没做好准备
All right, so we weren't prepared!
抱歉得用这种方法传达我的重点
l'm sorry l had to take such drastic measures to make my point.
但我是为你们的安全着想
But l...Look, I just want you guys to be safe.
危险
Danger!
漫臾
Unagi!
两千块可真不少
2000 bucks is a lot of money.
真想有个双胞胎兄弟
l wish l had a twin.
要去哪里才能找到
Where could l find someone...
跟我长得一模一样的人呢
...who looks exactly like me?
钱德勒
Chandler.
我感觉到是你
l sensed it was you.
什么
What?
漫臾
Unagi.
我永远全知
l'm always aware.
你知道漫臾就是鳗鱼吗
Are you aware that unagi is an eel?
什么事
What's up?
我不知道该做什么礼物
l can't figure out what to make Monica.
你可以做个你的笑话如何
Why don't you make her one of your little jokes?
我快急死了  好吗
l'm going crazy, okay?
你有没有什么看起来像是自制的东西
Do you have anything here that looks homemade?
这个她一定会喜欢
You know what? She'd love this.
这是阿波罗八号的模型
lt's an exact replica of Apollo 8.
我六年级做的
l made it in the sixth grade.
这个可以  我可以说
l could use that. l could say,
"你的爱让我飞上月亮"
"Your love sends me to the moon."
可是阿波罗八号没有登陆月球
Except Apollo 8 didn't actually land on the moon.
不过你可以写你的爱
But you could say, uh...
"让我绕行月球两圈后顺利返航"
"Your love lets me orbit the moon twice and return safely."
-慢着  我不能送这个  -为什么
- Wait a minute. l can't give this to her. - Why not?
因为旁边写着"罗斯队长"
lt says "Captain Ross" on the side.
底下写着"我讨厌莫妮卡"
And it says "l hate Monica" on the bottom.
危险
Danger!
鲑鱼手握寿司
Salmon-skin roll.
没错  亲爱的  这是我自己做的
Yes, honey, l made it myself.
我不能这么做  我不能这么做
l can't do it. l can't do it.
自己录的合辑  合辑
A mixed tape! A mixed tape!
可以交换礼物了吗
Hi! You ready to exchange gifts?
当然  你先来
Sure. Ok, you go first.
-好的  过来  -好
- Okay, come here. - Okay.
好  过来  我没有包装  因为我刚完成
Okay, now, it's not wrapped because l just finished it.
我录了一卷我觉得好听的浪漫情歌给你
But l made you a tape of what l think are all romantic songs.
好棒的礼物
What a great gift!
有《你今晚的模样》吗
ls "The Way You Look Tonight" on it?
你听了就知道
Maybe we'll have to listen and see.
我好喜欢喔  谢谢你  不客气
Oh, l love it! Thank you so much.
-你准备好要拆了吗  -好了
- You ready to open yours? - Yeah.
是袜子兔
lt's a sock bunny.
对  还记得有次我叫你小兔兔吗
Yeah. Yeah. Remember how l call you bunny?
有吗
Not really.
我叫过一次  以后我想多叫
l did one time. And l want to start doing it more.
-所以做了袜子小兔兔  -我懂了
- That's what this is about. - l see.
菲比也有做袜子兔
Phoebe makes sock bunnies.
不  没有  菲比做的是袜子兔子
No, she doesn't. What she makes, they're sock rabbits.
完全不一样...好吧
They're completely different. Okay, okay.
这不是我做的  对不起
Okay l didn't make it! I'm sorry.
我完全忘了今晚
l totally forgot about tonight
和亲手做礼物的事
and the fact that we're supposed to make the presents.
没关系  我...
lt's okay. I don't... uh...
不  当然有关系
No, no, it's not okay. It's not.
你那么...
I mean just... you're so incredible
你那么用心花那么多心血
that you went through all this time and effort
录情歌给我
to make this tape for me.
我要补偿你  我一定会的
l'll make this up to you. l will.
我会下厨房煮任何你想吃的菜
l am going to cook you anything you want in here.
进卧房玩任何你想玩的花样
And l'm going to do anything you want in there.
我的确花了很多心血
Well, l did put a lot of thought into the tape.
你还小  不该看的
You are way too young to have seen that.
再有一个半月就是你的生日
You know, your birthday's in a month and a half.
要是我又忘记准备礼物呢
What if l forget to get you a present for that too?
我会百分之百完全原谅你
You are totally and completely 100 percent forgiven.
-那个得拿去洗  -没错
- We've got to wash that. - Yeah.
你不是看上一件外套  又嫌它太贵
Do you remember that jacket you loved so much that was too expensive?
你对我已经够好了
You have done enough.
我要一早跑去买来送你
l'm gonna wake up early and get it for you.
不用啦  买黑色  别买咖啡色
No, you don't- -  Get it in black, not brown.
你的蛋糕好了
Your cake is ready.
俗话说得好  "做做爱  吃吃蛋糕"
lt's like that old saying, "Have sex, eat some cake."
小莫  老钱  我来拿汽水
Hey, Mon. Hey, Chan. Just getting a soda.
你是谁啊
Who the hell are you?
乔伊啊
l'm Joey.
你好咩  小妞儿
How are you doing?
错错错错错
No! No! No! No! No!
是你好吗  小妞
How you doing?
你好吗  真是的  卡尔  去走廊等我
How you doing? Damn it, Carl! Go wait in the hall.
我必须为卡尔的言行道歉
Look, l've got to apologize on behalf of Carl.
卡尔是谁啊
Who the hell is Carl?
我没说吗
Oh, Did l not mention?
我找卡尔来演我的双胞胎兄弟
Carl is a guy l hired to be my identical twin
好参加医学研究
for a medical research project.
有时妙计就在眼前  对吧
You know, Sometimes the good ideas are right in front of you, aren’t they?
我知道很扯  但搞不好会成功
I know it sounds crazy, but I think it might work, you know.
唯一的问题是卡尔的演技...
But the only problem is Carl's acting....
这是唯一的问题吗
The only problem?
对  他害我两年前
Yeah. He's the reason
痛失那支大广告  记得吗
l didn't get that big commercial a couple of years ago. Remember?
我们演兄弟  他却搞砸了
We were supposed to be brothers, but he messed up.
我可以吃一小块蛋糕吗
Can l get a piece of that little cake?
披萨  我们爱吃披萨  滚出去
Pizza! We like pizza! Get out!
-派特·赛贾克  -可以
- Pat Sajak? - Yep.
-亚历·崔贝克  -当然
- Alex Trebek? - Of course.
-恰克·乌勒利  -绝对行  菲比
- Chuck Woolery? - Definitely, Phoebe.
所有的综艺节目主持人
You will not find a single game-show host
我都能修理
whose ass l cannot kick.
-说  -说我们是漫臾
- Say it! - Say we are unagi!
它不在于是不是  而是有没有
lt's not something you are, it's something you have.
快说
Say it!
我可以轻易挣脱
l could easily get out of this...
但你们可能会死得很惨
...but there's a chance you could get very, very hurt!
卡尔  下一个就是我们了
Alright, Carl, we're next.
记住  这次不能怎样
Now remember, what is this not gonna be?
-重蹈那次广告的覆辙  -没错
- Another Minute Maid fiasco. - That's right.
你不能怎样
And what are you not gonna do?
-我不能讲话  因为...  -你还讲  卡尔
- l'm not gonna talk because- -  - Damn it, Carl!
下一组的资料...
Can l have the next one, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
乔伊和汤尼·崔比亚尼
Joey and Tony Tribbiani.
我们就是
That's us.
这是双胞胎的研究
But this is a study for identical twins.
没错  两千大洋
That's right. $2000.
但你们不是双胞胎啊
But you're not identical twins.
都是你啦
Damn it, Carl!
我的天啊
Oh, my good God.
快来倒数你最爱吃的食物吧
Continuing the countdown of your favorite meals.
今晚  第三名
Tonight, number three:
起司通心粉加切丁的热狗
Macaroni and cheese with cut-up hot dogs.
你对我够好了  别再费心了
Look, you have done enough. Okay? You have to stop this now.
我会的  但不是今晚
l will, but not tonight.
晚餐音乐
For dinner music,
我们就来听你录的带子好了
l thought we could listen to that tape that you made me.
那卷合辑
Oh, the mixed tape.
真的有《你今晚的模样》
"The Way You Look Tonight" is on here.
陪我跳舞
Dance with me.
你对我最好了
You are just the sweetest.
你每晚的模样我都爱  钱德勒
l love the way you look every night, Chandler.
所以我录这卷带子给你
That's why l made you this tape.
生日快乐  爱你的珍妮丝
Happy birthday! Love, Janice!
不  你才是对我最好了
No, you're the sweetest.
好  今天的课到此为止
Okay, ladies, that ends today's class.
记住  一定要平安
Just remember, be safe out there.
-你教得真好  -谢谢
- It's a great class. - Thanks.
我看得很仔细
l was watching.
不过我有一些问题
Hey. A couple of questions though.
刚才最后
You know that last move...
那个女人把你绊倒  压在地上
...where that woman tripped you and pinned you to the floor?
你接下来会怎么做
What would you do next?
她会拿钥匙来刺...
She'd take the keys and jam them in your- -
不是  是你会怎么做
No, no. What would you do next?
-你是说攻击者吗  -是的
- Who, me, the attacker? - Yes, that's right.
干嘛
Why?
我想偷袭两个女人  却没成功
l tried attacking two women. Did not work.
什么
What?
没关系  她们是我的朋友
No, it's okay. I mean, they're my friends.
我还跟其中一个结过婚
ln fact, l was married to one of them.
你偷击你的前妻啊
You attacked your ex-wife?
不  不是
Oh, no. No, no.
我试过偷袭她
l tried.
但没成功  所以才来找你
But l couldn't. That's why l'm here.
或许我们可以一起对付她们
Maybe we could attack them together!
你不同意啊
That's a no.
非常非常非常对不起
l am so, so, so, so sorry.
我会下厨房煮任何你想吃的菜
And l will cook anything you want in here...
进卧房玩任何你想玩的花样
...and do anything you want in there.
你当然得煮  你想得美喔
Yeah, you will! And are you kidding me?
别这样  这是我们的情人节
Come on, Monica, it's our Valentine's Day.
拜托  拜托  拜托啦
Please, please, please, please?
好吧
Okay.
我有趣的情人  甜蜜逗趣的情人
My funny valentine, sweet comic valentine!
-要进房间了吗  -你不许进
- So are we going in there? - l am!
你们逃不掉了
Nowhere to run.
我不喜欢坐这里  我要过去...
l don't like sitting up here. l'm gonna go over- -
瑞秋  是他们先来的
No, Rach. they got here first.
-罗斯在干嘛  -危险
- Why is Ross doing that? - Danger!
天啊
Oh, my God!
他干嘛扑向那两个女人
Why is he jumping on those women?
我们应该去帮她们
We should help them.
我看她们不需要帮忙
l don't think they need any help.